

Contact

Phone

+39 3925667769

Email

amarcomiglietta@gmail.com

Address

Via Padova, 330 - Milano (MI) - 20132

Hard Skills

- Process Automation
- Testing (Quality Assurance)
- Agile Methodology
- Python
- Selenium
- Robot Framework
- JDBC
- SOAP UI
- AngularJS
- Java
- C#

Soft Skills

- Customer Care
- Problem Solving
- Creativity
- Active Listening
- Communication
- Proactive Approach
- Perseverance
- Resilience
- Flexibility

Antonio Marco Miglietta

QA Automation Specialist

About me

Quality Assurance professional with 10 years of experience, focused on developing automated solutions to meet clients' needs. Always been **creative**, **proposing** and **detail-oriented**, he started his journey in the IT world in 2013, working on **many projects** across **different industries** and **groups**, gathering good feedback and improving both his personal and professional skills. He is now a part of a **growing team**, delivering an increasing number of solutions and playing a **key-role** in the company.

Experience

O 11/2023 - NOW

Hays - [Remote]

QA Automation Specialist

Main activities performed:

- Maintain and enhance a custom C# framework used for API testing.
- Analysis, design, creation and execution of TCs to expand various suites.
- Develop (with python) utilities to facilitate testing processes. The utilities focus mainly on **data manipulation** and file creation (such as creating **xml** or **jmx** files).
- Create test suite for performance load testing component (JMeter).
- POC of new framework for GUI testing (Python w/ Cypress and Cucumber)
- Create and maintain Azure DevOps pipelines using YAML files.

Q 09/2019 - 11/2023

Assioma.Net - TXT Group - [Milano]

QA Automation Specialist

Main activities performed:

- Build-up of a framework (python w/ wc3270) for automating mainframe processes (z/OS) with the goal of <u>making a pre-existing set of automated processes</u> (developed in VBScript language) <u>more stable, usable and scalable</u>. Consequent process of migrating existing automatons to the new technology (testing, running in parallel with existing processes, etc.).
- Implementation of **automated processes** (testing/RPA) following each phase of the implementation (analysis of functional needs, identification of the most suitable technology, development of all technical aspects, drafting of technical/functional documents, user support and maintenance of the offered service)
- Orchestration of the above processes using **Jenkins** (Groovy pipeline scripts)
- **Development of a custom library** for handling input parameters provided to Jenkins pipelines
- Automation of the **interaction process with a proprietary simulator** in the authorization domain (input file creation, simulator invocation, output file parsing)
- Development of utilities and various tools to accompany the above
- Expansion of a more or less complex set of activities in UAT and related customer support
- Interaction with various test environments (SIT/UAT), analysis, reporting and resolution of any related critical issues
- Creating web application (AngularJS / Java) to simplify the process of scheduling activities managed through the above. Goal: allow Test Managers (functional) to easily enter/edit/delete scheduled activities in the UAT environment bypassing the intervention of a more technical resource.

Technologies used:

- <u>Programming/scripting languages:</u> Java, Groovy, Python, Bash, RubyOnRails, Robot Framework, AngularJS, HTML, CSS, Javascript
- <u>DBs:</u> Oracle, DB2, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server
- Tools/Platforms: Jenkins, Confluence, Jira, DBeaver, PyCharm, VSCode

Language



Education

2012

High School DiplomaLiceo Scientifico G.Banzi Bazoli - Lecce

2013

Master

ELIS - ICT Academy - Roma

Hobbies & More

- Art & Design
- Motorsport
- IT & Gaming
- Movies
- Photography
- Architecture

O 04/2016 - 09/2019

IBM Client Innovation Center - [Bergamo]

IT Automation Specialist

Main activities performed:

- Analysis, design, creation and execution of Test Cases by developing scripts (using IBM tools such as Rational Test Workbench) with a view to no-regression testing (front-end/back-end) and subdividing them into Test Suites (according to the peculiarities of each of them)
- Managing test environments: troubleshooting of various kinds on VMs used
- Preliminary analysis of possible defects (log, database, body-response REST calls).
- Creation of a work plan following analysis of new developments to be completed.
- Managing timelines and activities in a production process with well defined timelines within a Scrum-Driven (Agile) team.

06/2013 - 04/2019

Technisblu SRL - [Roma]

JR SW Developer

Main activities performed:

- Third-party product **configuration tool development** (XML/YML/CSV generation from different inputs).
- Basic maintenance of test environments (S.O. RedHat, DB Oracle).
- **Support** and **bug-fix** on **web-based applications** (Java EE) used in the field of expense management and budgets.
- Product/module testing, analyzing identified bugs and tracking them on bug tracking platform.
- Interaction with the **final customer** (international scope) for everything related to **UAT activities**.
- Performing module testing and analysis of the same, resulting in generation of case reports.

Personal Data

In compliance with the GDPR and the Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize you to use and process my personal details contained in this document

M. M. A.